Guide to the Ron Howard papers, 1958-1999 MS0766.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Photographs, 1975-1998; MS0766 Series 1; 6 Linear feet (Box 11, Box 12, Box 9, Box 10, Box 7, Box 8, Box 5, Box 6, Box 3, Box 4, Box 1, Box 2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game vs. Rutgers, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game at University of Mass., 1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game at Georgia Tech, 1990 ca. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. University of Mass.-w/Bill Clinton and Chelsea Clinton in attendance (with negatives), 02/04/1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game w/Red Auerbach in Attendance (with negatives), 1995 ca. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. Connecticut, NCAA tournament, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. U. Mass. (with negatives), 1995 ca. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. Florida, 1995 ca. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. Temple, 1995 ca. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game, 1996 ca. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game v. Maryland, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game US Air Arena (with negatives), 1998 ca. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game (with negatives), 1999 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball-Orange Bowl game w/Bobby Bowden (with negatives), 1990 ca. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball NCAA tournament vs. University of Alabama-Birmingham (UAB) (with negatives), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball NCAA playoff game vs. Michigan in Seattle, Washington, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball game (with negatives), 1994 ca. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball pre-season NIT tournament in New York, 1995 ca. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball reunion (with negatives), 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball team, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball team, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball team (with negatives), 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's basketball team on party cruise, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Men's crew (with negatives), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Miscellaneous awards ceremony, 1996 ca. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Miscellaneous lecture in Marvin Center with President Trachtenberg, 1996 ca. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Monumental Celebration/commencement, 1995 ca. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Monumental Celebration at Union Station, 1995 ca. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Monumental Celebration at Union Station with GW mascot "George", 1995 ca. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Morris, E.K., Chairman of the Board of Trustees, 1975 ca. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: New Hall groundbreaking, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: New student orientation, 1994 ca. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: New student orientation week, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    See also videotapes - Admissions Greeting, 1992
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Olympic torch relay, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Opening Convocation, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Osgood, Charles speaking to a group at GW, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Party for unidentified man, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personal economic summit conference w/Senator Warren Rudman (with negatives), 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:George Steinbrenner, 05/1982 (Box 10, Folder 6.1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Earl Warren, 1965 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Jerry Lewis, 01/1997 (Box 10, Folder 6.3)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:David Eisenhower, 1985 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.4)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Robert Redford, 09/1974 (Box 10, Folder 6.5)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Bart Starr-Green Bay quarterback, 1968 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.6)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Senator Christopher Dodd, 1996 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.7)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Richard Gephart, 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.8)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Lloyd Elliott and DC Mayor Marion Barry, 05/1982 (Box 10, Folder 6.9)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Cokie Roberts, 1996 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Martina Navratalova, tennis player, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6.11)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Dan Quayle, 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.12)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Colin Powell, 1985 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.13)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Vincent Price, 1965 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.14)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Jeane Kirkpatrick, former U.N. Ambassador, undated (Box 10, Folder 6.15)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Joe E. Brown, Comedian, 1965 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.16)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:David Hartman, 02/1988 (Box 10, Folder 6.17)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Walter Mondale, Vice President and brother Clarence Mondale, GW Professor, 1980 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.18)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Jack Kemp, 1996 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.19)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Don Hoddel, 1990 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Personalities/Celebrities:Shamon Perez, former Israeli Prime Minister, 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 6.21)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Pleacher, John K. -School of Education award in teaching, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Quayle, Dan (autographed), 1990 ca. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Rally sending off women's basketball team to NCAA tournament (with negatives), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Reagan, President Ronald, receiving an honorary degree from GW, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Reception w/Marion Barry, 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Reception w/President Trachtenberg, Edward "Skip" Gnehm, etc., 1992 ca. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Reich, Robert, 1997 ca. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Ribbon cutting for new room (Strong Hall?), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Roberts, Cokie & Steve (with negatives), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Russell, Mark at GW, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Scenes of Washington D.C. - Jefferson Memorial, FDR Memeorial, Lincoln Memorial, White House, Vietnam Veteran's Memorial, Capitol and Statue of Freedom restoration, aerial photos, (with negatives), 1985 ca.-1998 ca. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Scheiffer, Bob of CBS news at National Press Club, 1997 ca. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Spring summit w/Gorbachev and President Bush (with negatives), 1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Student association function, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Student/Campus scenes-miscellaneous, 1994-1998 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Students-Miscellaneous, 1995 ca. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Theatre - HMS Pinafore cast party, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Thomas, Evan at GWU (with negatives), 1998 ca. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel at function, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel, 1988 ca. 1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Selected items from this folder are described below. Please note that this is not a comprehensive list of the materials within this folder
  - President Stephen Joel Trachtenberg, undated (Box 11, Folder 3.1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel & students w/D.C. city council, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel & students visit Mount Vernon, Va., 1995 ca. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel receiving 10,000 student applications, 1993 ca. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel awarding medal to unidentified man, 1996 ca. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Troubadours, 05/1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Trustees Gate, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Vice-President Al Gore giving speech in Marvin Center, 1995 ca. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Vice-President Dan Quayle on Meet the Press (with negatives), 1990 ca. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Warner, Mark & the young democrats, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Warner, Mark (GW class of 1977) - campaign for Senate, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: White House Christmas photos, 1995 ca. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's Athletics Alumni Honorees, 1985 ca. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's athletics banquet (with negatives), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball awards banquet, 1995 ca. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game (with negatives), 1988 ca. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, including mascot "George" (with negatives), 1990 ca. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, NCAA tournament vs. UAB, (with negatives), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, NCAA tournament vs. DePaul, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, NCAA tournament vs. Drake, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's basketball game, NCAA tournament vs. Temple, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - George Washington University, Events, and Campus: Women's volleyball game, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Personal Photographs of Ron Howard: World Series baseball game, New York Yankees v. Atlanta Braves, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Personal Photographs of Ron Howard: Ron Howard-Personal, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Personal Photographs of Ron Howard: Ron Howard-Personal, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Personal Photographs of Ron Howard: Ron Howard-Personal, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Memorabilia, 1970-1998; MS0766 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Box 14)
  This series consists of banners, towels, pennants, stickers, buttons, key chains, coasters, and other memorabilia. These materials range in date from 1970 ca.-1998 ca., with a number of items from GW's 175th anniversary celebration in 1996.
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Button-sized adhesive stickers: The George Washington University, 1821 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Banner: The George Washington University, Washington DC 175th Anniversary 1821-1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Bookmark: The George Washington University Washington DC Academic Honors, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Flags (hand held miniatures): The George Washington University 175th Anniversary, Washington DC, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Foam hatchets: GW Colonials (2), undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Key chains: GW Colonials The George Washington University, The George Washington University 1821, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Medallions: The George Washington University Inaugural Ball January 20, 1993 (1), The George Washington University 1821 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Metal ruler: The George Washington Law Association, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Oversized ceramic circular coaster: Reunion Weekend May 15-17, 1981 The George Washington University 1821 (1), Oversized ceramic square coaster: General Alumni Association (1) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Pennants: George Washington University (2), undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Pins: Centuries Campaign The George Washington University (2), 175 (1), GW Colonials (1), undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Posters: The George Washington University Washington DC, Sciences, Humanities and Social Sciences, Engineering, International Relations, Communications, Business and Management, Arts (2), undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Stickers: The George Washington University (6), undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: The George Washington University Washington DC Parent Services "I swapped my kid for this bag at GW", undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Tie clip: The George Washington University 1821, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Towels: GW Colonials (2), George Washington (1), George Washington University Colonials Basketball It's like workin' out! GW Colonials (1), undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: White cup: George Washington University, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Yellow notepad: The George Washington University Washington DC, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: Matchbook "GWU Freshman Banquet, Class of 1985" (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Banners, Stickers, Towels, Etc.: George Washington University notepad, 24 assorted pages, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Buttons: By George! The George Washington University, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Buttons: G.W. Reunion 1981 (3) (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Buttons: GWU We Made It! SGBA 1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Buttons: I Love GW, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Buttons: I'm a Fan of 'Mr. GW', undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Buttons: The George Washington University 175th Anniversary 1821-1996 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Buttons: The George Washington University Washington DC, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Videotapes, 1986-1998; MS0766 Series 4; 1 Linear foot (Box 15)
  This series consists of eighteen videotapes ranging in date from 1986-98. They include the Class of 1936 fifty year reunion, the Convocation honoring President Ronald Reagan, Commencements from 1991 and 1995, Walter Cronkite on the Kalb Report, and various recruitment videos.
  - Admissions Greeting, 02/01/1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    See also photos - New Student Orientation week, 1992
  - Alumni Association Dinner, David Eisenhower, 11/06/1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1936 Fifty Year Reunion, 06/1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Convocation: Honoring President Ronald Reagan and Mrs. Nancy Reagan, 03/28/1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    See also Photos
  - George Washington University Basketball & "George" on News 7 WJLA-TV (ABC) at Eleven, 01/20/1994 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - H.M.S. Pinafore, 06/04/1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Lloyd and Betty Elliott", made by Rita Oakes Productions, 05/17/1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Commencement - Speech by Richard Weitz, 05/1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The George Washington University, Connections, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The George Washington University, Connections Video Tour, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The George Washington University, recruiting tape, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The George Washington University, The Neighborhood Video, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Commencement, 05/14/1995 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - The Kalb Report Ethics in Journalism with Walter Cronkite. Also, program from The Kalb Report, 04/13/1998 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The Real Movie Tour, The George Washington University, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - The Saving of the President, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Toward the 21st Century, The George Washington University, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - "Something Happens Here" - Admissions video, 1996 ca. (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Certificates, Awards, Personal items, 1977-1996; MS0766 Series 5; 1 Linear foot (Box 16)
  This series consists of awards and certificates and miscellaneous personal items of Ron Howard. Certificates from fraternities include Phi Sigma Kappa, and Omicron Delta Kappa. Awards include those given to Howard for his 20, 25, and 30 years of service to GW, as well as his 1977 GW Award, given in "special recognition to those people who have made The George Washington University a better place to be." Also in this series are photos of Howard receiving his GW Award in 1977, a letter of thanks from President Trachtenberg for the work Howard did on his Inauguration, and a souvenir book of the Basketball Hall of Fame, which includes Red Auerbach, former coach of the Boston Celtics and GW Class of 1940.
  - Certificate of Appreciation from Phi Sigma Kappa, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Plaque: Twenty years of service to George Washington University, 1964-1984 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Certificate from Phi Sigma Kappa Fraternity, declaring Howard a life member, 04/24/1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Certificate of Membership into Omicron Delta Kappa Society, 04/21/1977 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Recognition for 25 years of service to George Washington University, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Framed and signed drawing of the George Washington University, Alumni House, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - GW Award given to Ron Howard - correspondence, press releases, guidelines, photos, 05/08/1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - President Stephen Joel Trachtneberg's inauguration with letter of thanks to Howard, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Certificate of Recognition given to Howard for 30 years of service to George Washington University (with program), 1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Biographical clippings of Howard - Newspaper clipping, The GW Hatchet, article: "Howard appointed to expanded position"; GW Report, article: "Sandra Lear to Retire-Howard to succeed her," April 28, 1986; Monday Report, article "Ron Howard Joins Alumni Office", 09/08/1980 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Tickets and press pass for Hatchet - Basketball ticket: Presidential Classic, Jan. 6, 1973; Press pass for Howard as photographer from The Hatchet, 1968 -- 1969; Tickets: A Convocation in Honor of the Fortieth President of the United States & Mrs. Reagan, 03/28/1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Washington Press Club Foundation Congressional Dinner program. Cover states: "Wonder Woman for President,", 01/24/1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Healy, Jerry, Ed. The Official Souvenir Book of the Basketball Hall of Fame. West Springfield, Mass: The Bordeaux Company, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Plaque: The George Washington University Marvin Center Ronald W. Howard Governing Board, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Small marble plaque: The Friends of the Libraries in Appreciation for Service, 1986-1992 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - GW Award - Small silver bust of George Washington and marble base, 05/08/1977 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Medallion: Centuries Campaign The George Washington University, 02/07/1996 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Medallion: President's Medal, The George Washington University, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    With buff and blue neck ribbon. Inscription reads "Mr. GW" Ronald W. Howard, 1999 - presented by Stephen Joel Trachtenberg, President
- Slides, 1958-1983; MS0766 Series 2; 1 Linear foot (Box SHARED Box 11)